

# **Cesar Napoles**

Nationality: Cuban Date of birth: 24/11/1990

Skype: live:juliocesarnapolespuente in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jcnapoles

**Website:** <u>cesarnapoles.com</u>

### **ABOUT ME**

I offer more than 10 years of experience as Computer Engineer, highly prepared as a software developer, in analysis and technical consultancy.

I am used to solving problems and unforeseen events autonomously, and with the ability to successfully combine different tasks. I am characterized by responsibility, proactivity, organization, and commitment to work.

Ease of communication and great ability to work as a team. High willingness for professional improvement according to the work environment, the tools, and technologies used.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer / Project Manager

Amaris Consulting [ 06/05/2021 - Current ]

City: Barelona | Country: Spain

- Analysis, design and development of applications.
- Technical and functional consulting.
- Development, maintenance and migration of legacy applications, JAVA, Angular, Spring, React.
- Development and integration of APIs
- Planning, executing, and closing projects

**Technical environment:** Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Spring, Angular, React, SQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, HBase, GIT, AWS, JUNIT, Jest, Cypress, Maven, Jira, Budget planner

### **Software Engineer**

**Isern Patentes y Marcas** [ 29/07/2018 – 01/05/2021 ]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain

- Analysis, design and development of applications.
- Web developer
- Database developer, maintenance, user support.

### **Completed tasks:**

- IsernTools, web management tool.
- Similar Files Detector v1.0. Artificial Intelligence Project in collaboration with UPC (Polytechnic University of Catalonia)
- Import of Bulletins. Automated program for downloading and uploading Bulletins in Database
- ISERN Images. Image processing program for Isern users.
- Client with an interface to consume web services published by the OEPM (www.oepm.es)

**Technical environment:** Java EE, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 Soapui, JUnit, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring Boot, jQuery, Maven, Spring Roo, BIRT (Business Intelligence and Reporting Tools), Soap / Rest (JSON, XML), Bootstrap, JPA-Hibernate, Intersystems Cache, MySQL, SVN, GIT, Apache CXF.

# **Full Stack Developer**

*Indra* [ 27/07/2016 - 05/06/2018 ]

City: Montevideo | Country: Uruguay

- Analysis, design, and development of business applications.
- Technical and functional consulting.

### Completed tasks:

- InGRID MDM project for the management and estimation of electrical measurements with implementation in Uruguay.
- Maintaining the quality of the code, automating tasks, and optimizing processes seeking a better user experience.
- API Rest Inventory for exchange with external tools of the client company.

**Technical environment:** BigData Cloudera (Hadoop, MapReduce, HBase), Spring, JPA, Hibernate, Quartz, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring Boot, jQuery, Maven, Spring Roo, BIRT (Business Intelligence and Reporting Tools), Soap / Rest (JSON, XML), Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Oracle, PostgreSQL, Apache CXF.

### **QA** tester

Universidad de las Ciencias Informaticas [ 03/09/2014 – 15/07/2016 ]

City: Havana | Country: Cuba

• Quality Management Tester of projects developed at the University of Computer Science

### **Completed tasks:**

- Functional Tests, Design and Execution of Test Cases
- Test Plan Design
- Automated Tests

**Technical environment:** Selenium, JMeter, JUnit, Linux, Microsoft Office, Open Office, Redmine.

# Software developer

Universidad de las Ciencias Informaticas [ 03/09/2012 – 15/08/2014 ]

City: Havana | Country: Cuba

Web developer

#### Completed tasks:

• Development of tools to manage components (services and dependencies) in XAUCE (Business framework).

Technical environment: PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ExtJS

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **Computer Science Engineer, Informatics Engineering**

**Universidad de las Ciencias Informaticas** [ 08/2009 – 07/2014 ]

City: Havana | Country: Cuba | Website: www.uci.cu

### Master's degree in Big Data with Phyton

Escuela Superior de Informatica CIPSA [ 15/06/2019 – 15/06/2020 ]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain | Website: cipsa.net

# Master's degree in Java EE

**Escuela Superior de Informatica CIPSA** [ 15/06/2018 – 10/06/2019 ]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain | Website: cipsa.net

# **Cloud administration (Azure, AWS, Google Cloud)**

**Amaris Consulting** [ 10/11/2022 - 10/06/2023 ]

City: Barcelona | Country: Spain | Website: amaris.com

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Spanish

Other language(s):

# **English**

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

# **DIGITAL SKILLS**

# **Programming languages**

Java / JavaScript / HTML5 / CSS3 / PHP / JPA / Typescript / hibernate ORM / SQL

### **Frameworks**

Bootstrap / Spring / Angular / React / Maven / JavaScript - JQuery / Spring Quartz / HADOOP

### **Version Control**

Git / SVN / LiquiBase

# **Testing**

Cypress / JUNIT / Apache Jmeter / SoapUi / Selenium / Jest / cURL / Postman

# **Management**

JIRA / Redmine / Trello

#### CI/CD

Docker / Jenkins / GitHub, GitHub Actions

### **Cloud Platforms**

AWS / Heroku / Azure

# **Agile**

Scrum

### **IDEs**

Spring Tool Suite (STS) / VSCode, Visual Studio / JetBrains Intellij Idea / Visual Paradigm / BIRT report designer / Eclips e / NetBeans / DBeaver